<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Escience Lazycache Gcp on CamHD Video Analysis</title>
    <link>https://camhd-analysis.github.io/public-www/categories/escience-lazycache-gcp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Escience Lazycache Gcp on CamHD Video Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://camhd-analysis.github.io/public-www/categories/escience-lazycache-gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Notes on Trying out Deis Workflow on Google Container Engine</title>
      <link>https://camhd-analysis.github.io/public-www/post/2017-02-13-trying-out-deis-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camhd-analysis.github.io/public-www/post/2017-02-13-trying-out-deis-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Over the last couple of weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the range of offerings from Google Cloud Platform. I started out working with base Google Compute Engine (GCE) virtual instances, as it&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;ground floor&amp;rdquo; on the technology pyramid and seemed like a good place to start. With Docker as a common platform, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty straightforward to spin up single GCE instances which automatically load and run a Docker image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Tour of LazyCache Part II, Deploying to Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <link>https://camhd-analysis.github.io/public-www/post/2017-01-25-deploying-to-google-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camhd-analysis.github.io/public-www/post/2017-01-25-deploying-to-google-cloud/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE Feb 14 2017: For a bunch of reasons (mostly having to do with triggering CI builds), I decided lazycache-deploy didn&amp;rsquo;t need to be its own repo. It&amp;rsquo;s now a sub-directory of https://github.com/amarburg/go-lazycache-app. I&amp;rsquo;ve done an imperfect modification of the text below&amp;hellip;
For totally arbitrary, er, I mean perfectly reasonable reasons, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to target Google Cloud Platform as my strawman &amp;ldquo;commercial cloud&amp;rdquo; provider. I still believe there&amp;rsquo;s a use case for deploying the software &amp;mdash; or some subset of it &amp;mdash; on a local or lab machine, but it certainly makes a lot of sense to have the server capable of running in the cloud, whether it&amp;rsquo;s public or strictly private to service a set of local compute instances, so this seemed like a good place to start.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>